AMANDA RICHWALSKI

158 Lotus Dr, Apt. 1 | Carmel, IN 46032 | (312) 285-7893 | Amanda.Richwalski@gmail.com | LinkedIn.com/in/arichwalski

DEVELOPER

Java developer professional with eight-years' experience as a human resource and administrative professional, that is able to transfer soft skills to your organization, and capable of managing technology projects from concept to completion with remarkable deadline sensitivity. Strong analytical skills, combined with experience and training in programming techniques; as well as compatible team player through complete project cycles, testing and final implementation.

SKILLS

Languages: Java, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, ¡Query, Bootstrap

Software: MS Office, Jazz ATS, Zenefits HRIS, ADP, Intuit Payroll, QuickBooks, SharePoint, Microsoft ERP, Concur, Expensify

Operating Systems: Windows, macOS Project Management: Agile/Scrum

EMPLOYMENT

HR and Office Manager | Kivvit - Public Relations | 2015 - 2016

Served as Human Resource Associate for all staff including Chicago, IL, Miami, FL, New York, NY, and Asbury Park, NJ. Contributed to new hire recruitment and pre-screening through recruiting software Jazz, media postings, and conducted pre-screening interviews. Executed new hire on-boarding: new hire contracts, IT set-up, new hire benefits and company procedures training. Administered employee HR records upkeep through HRIS Zenefits. Maintained and updated the company benefits plan, and assisted with open enrollment meetings, trainings, and recordkeeping. Processed semi-monthly payroll utilizing Intuit Payroll. Managed office productivity by processing orders for office supplies, meals, and technology equipment for all offices. Regulated corporate cell phone account by adding new lines of service, as well as process cellular changes. Implemented technology initiatives and manage outsourced IT department. Maintained the company website and intranet, as well as created updates.

- Administered implementation project of new company intranet SharePoint site.
- Conducted research, implementation, and training for Jazz ATS.
- Developed out-of-date Company Handbook with direction from general counsel.
- Organized the client "Chicago Holiday and Kivvit Launch 2015 Party" for over 100 guests.

Administrative Accounting Coordinator | DMC, Inc., - Technology and Automation | 2013 - 2015

Managed client account portfolios for Chicago, IL, Boston, MA, and Denver, CO. Accounts receivables management, included creating time and expense invoices for customers through QuickBooks, as well as contacting customers with past due balances. Processed customer, check and ACH, payments through QuickBooks. Reviewed employee weekly timesheets, and sent to Project Managers for approval. Processed customer and internal PO's through QuickBooks and SharePoint. Administered employee expense reports, reconciled American Express statements, as well as general bookkeeping. Generated, printed, and distributed ad hoc financial reports for the Project Management team.

Office Manager | Telezygology (TZ) Inc. / Product Development Technologies (PDT) Inc., - Technology Security | 2010 - 2012

Managed the Chicago headquarter office for TZ Inc. and supported administrative operations for sister company PDT Inc. Served as Human Resource Associate for all staff including United States, Canada, Europe, and Australia. Contributed to new hire recruitment and pre-screening, conducted new hire orientation for staff, benefit administration and reconciliation, as well as maintained employee records including COBRA and EEO-1. Processed semi-monthly payroll utilizing ADP, personal reimbursement expense reports, and general bookkeeping. Scheduled conference calls, planned corporate events, and made all travel arrangements for staff.

- Conducted research for CFO to identify top vendor products for implementation of a new corporate expense reporting system; trained employees on new system.
- Oversaw the transfer of database and implementation of new ADP system for payroll.

Human Resources Assistant | A & R Security Services – Security Service Provider | 2008 – 2010

Assisted with administration of recruiting events, media postings, and conducted pre-screening interviews. Managed the human resource communications for over 1,000 employees among a high-turnover industry. Conducted quarterly benefit and certification analysis of employee records (COBRA, FMLA, EEO-1). Prepared HR documents including employment and background verification, vacation logs, and updates to employment laws.

EDUCATION

Accelerated Learning Program, Java | Eleven Fifty Academy, Fishers, IN | 2016

Master of Business Administration | Benedictine University, Lisle, IL | 2014

Bachelor of Science in Human Resource Management | Purdue University, Hammond, IN | 2008

ORGANIZATIONS

Society Human Resource Management National Society for Hispanic Professionals National Association of Professional Women